Guide to the William R. Ewald papers, 1947-1970.
Ewald, William R., papers, 1947-1970
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William R. Ewald papers, 1947-1970.
4876
William R. Ewald
5 cubic ft.
Projects, articles, maps, audiotapes, reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Projects, articles, maps, audiotapes, reports, and other materials pertaining to Ewald's career as a planner.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Development consultant, planner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Projects, articles, maps, audiotapes, reports, and other materials pertaining to Ewald's career as a planner. Included are projects in Arkansas and the Ozarks, and material concerning the Appalachian Institute, Santa Barbara's Alternative Comprehensive Community Environmental Study System, the American Institute of Planners, and environmentalism.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ewald, William R.; Alternative Comprehensive Community Environmental Study System (Santa Barbara, California); American Institute of Planners.; Appalachian Institute.
Subjects:
Planning--Arkansas.; Environmentalism.; Environmental policy.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Projects
  - A General Development Plan for Bloomfield Hills, 1947 (Box 1)
  - The Arkansas Encyclopedia, 1957 (Box 1)
  - 9th Annual Community Accomplishment Contest, 1958 (Box 1)
  - AIDC 6-Point Preparedness Program, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Towards Accelerating the Economic Growth of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, 1960 (Box 1)
  - An Industrial History of Arkansas, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Downtown Streets and Places, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Research for the Development of Appalachia, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Report of the Appalachian Institute Committee, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Change/Challenge/Response: A Development Policy for New York State, with correspondence and review by Lewis Mumford, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Development Programs and Recommendations for Arkansas: Parts I-IV, Appendix A and B, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Conclusions and Recommendations to Robert K. Wheeler re Development of the Champion and Berkshire Inn Properties (in Great Barrington), 1965 (Box 1)
  - Appalachian Institute Prospectus/Budget/Funding, 1966 (Box 1)
  - The Ozark Way - Proposal for a Scenic Highway from Arkadelphia to Sringfield, 1966 (Box 1)
  - A Street Graphics Systems for Baltimore County: Commercial, Manufacturing and Institutional, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Street Graphics: A Concept and a System, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Call It Epoch: Managing the Environment for the World Ahead, Two Editions, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Access: The Santa Barbara Regional Pilot Process. Alternate Comprehensive Community Enviornmental Study System, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Access: Design Phase; Report to the South Coast Region; Documentation, Vols. A and B, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Information, Perception and Regional Policy: Access Project Design Phase, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Geocoding Data for Display and Policy Analysis, 1977 (Box 2)
    Vol. 1 - The Potenital of the Access Process re Energy, Environment and the Economy. Multi-State, State and Multi-County Applications. Vol. 2 - Technology from the User Perspective. Proceedings of the Santa Barbara Conference
- Articles and speeches
  - "The Economy of Foresight in Community Development," The American City, Nov. 1952 (Box 2)
  - "Urban Renewal: A Prime Source for Plant Sites," Industrial Development, Feb. 1961 (Box 2)
  - "The Cityscape," Planning, 1962 (Box 2)
  - "What the Future Offers...and Demands," AIA Journal. (Edwald is not the author, but is quoted extensively), Nov. 1969 (Box 2)
  - "The Psychological Limits of Population," The Center Magazine. A Publication of the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1970 (Box 2)
  - "Planning for the New Free Time - Leisure, Retirement, Idleness, Recreation," La Costa, California, Mar. 10, 1970 (Box 2)
  - "The Ecology Problem: Understanding Humans as Animals is Not the Same as Understanding Humans as Beings," Brown Alumni Magazine, July 1970 (Box 2)
  - "Looking Forward with a 'Planners' Planner," Center Report, Oct. 1970 (Box 2)
  - "A Third Force to Deal with Change," The Center Magazine, Nov. 1970 (Box 2)
  - "Street Graphics," HUD Challenge, Oct. 1973 (Box 2)
  - "Can Planning Save Us," np (Box 2)
  - "Chart 1a, 1c, 2d, 3a, 3b," np (Box 2)
- The AIP 50 Year Conference
  - Planning Documents for the Conference, 1965-1970 (Box 2)
  - "The Next 50 Years," Tapes 1-20, 1967 (Box 2)
  - "The Next 50 Years," Tapes 21-60, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Portland Conference, 18 tapes, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Portland Conference, draft transcript (Box 4)
  - Arkansas Conference, "The Next 50 Years," 5 tapes (Box 4)
  - "The Next 50 Years," John Platt, Harold Taylor, Joseph Sittler, Ralph G. H. Siu, John E. Burchard, Robert C. Wood, Herman Kahn. 9 tapes. Broadcast over WBAI-fm, Pacific Radio (Box 4)
  - "Discussion with Vickers," 2 tapes (Box 4)
  - AIP Altantic Regional Meeting, "Conference 2020," New York City, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Commissioned Papers: (Box 5)
    "The Present Situation - Its Implications," Boris Pushkarev
    "If Present Trends Continue," Jerome P. Pickard
    "A Practical Utopia for the Region," David A. Wallace
    "New Responsibilities for Government," Marion Clawson
    "New Roles for Private Enterprise," Herman Kahn
  - Six maps (Box 5)
  - Nine tapes (Box 5)
  - "Faustain Powers and Human Choices: Some 21st Century Technological and Economic Issues," Herman Kahn and Anthony J. Wiener, 1967 (Box 5)
  - "Planning and the Planning Profession: The Past Fifty Years 1917-1967 ," Russell Van Nest Black (Box 5)
  - Environment and Change: The Next Fifty Years (Box 5)
  - Environment and Change: The Next Fifty Years (Box 5)